http://www.askbobrankin.com/privacy-policy.html

Need tech support? Ask BobYour Computer or Internet Question!
(Enter search keywords, or ask your question.)
Recommended:
Free Online College
Did you take the Backup Survey?
Tell me YOUR most urgent backup questions!
PRIVACY POLICY
The policy: This privacy policy notice is for this website, AskBobRankin.com, and served by AskBobRankin, 1 Old Millpond Lane, Warwick NY 10990, governs the privacy of those who use it. The purpose of this policy is to explain to you how we control, process, handle and protect your personal information while browsing or using this website, including your rights under current laws and regulations. If you do not agree to the following policy you should cease viewing / using this website.
Policy key definitions:
"I", "our", "us", or "we" refer to the business, AskBobRankin.com.
"you", "the user" refer to the person(s) using this website.
GDPR means General Data Protection Regulation Act.
PECR means Privacy & Electronic Communications Regulation.
ICO means Information Commissioner's Office.
Cookies mean small files stored on a users computer or device.
PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA
Under the GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) we control and / or process any personal information about you electronically using the following lawful bases.
We are exempt from registration in the ICO Data Protection Register because you grant us Consent based on this document detailing your privacy rights and our use of your data. Please note that we do not retain your visit information but we do retain any comments left on the site in perpetuity. If, as determined by us, the lawful basis upon which we process your personal information changes, we will endeavor to notify you about the change and any new lawful basis to be used if required. We shall stop processing your personal information if the lawful basis used is no longer relevant.
YOUR INDIVIDUAL RIGHTS
Under the GDPR your rights are as follows. You can read more about your rights in details here;
the right to be informed;
the right of access;
the right to rectification;
the right to erasure;
the right to restrict processing;
the right to data portability;
the right to object; and
the right not to be subject to automated decision-making including profiling.
You also have the right to complain to the ICO if you feel there is a problem with the way we are handling your data.
We handle subject access requests in accordance with the GDPR.
INTERNET COOKIES
We use cookies on this website to provide you with a better user experience. We do this by placing a small text file on your device / computer hard drive to track how you use the website, to record or log whether you have seen particular messages that we display, to keep you logged into the website where applicable, to display relevant adverts or content, referred you to a third party website.
Some cookies are required to enjoy and use the full functionality of this website.
We use a cookie control system which allows you to accept the use of cookies, and control which cookies are saved to your device / computer. Some cookies will be saved for specific time periods, where others may last indefinitely. Your web browser should provide you with the controls to manage and delete cookies from your device, please see your web browser options.
Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to this and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy page.
In addition, other advertisers that we work with also use cookies in a similar manner: If you would prefer to opt out then you may disable cookies within your Web browser.
DATA SECURITY AND PROTECTION
We ensure the security of any personal information we hold by using secure data storage technologies and precise procedures in how we store, access and manage that information. Our methods meet the GDPR compliance requirement.
TRANSPARENT PRIVACY EXPLANATIONS
We have provided some further explanations about user privacy and the way we use this website to help promote a transparent and honest user privacy methodology.
SPONSORED LINKS, AFFILIATE TRACKING & COMMISSIONS
Our website also contains adverts, sponsored and affiliate links on some pages. These may be served through our advertising partners; Google Adsense, Ezoic, Amazon Affiliates, or similar. We only use trusted advertising partners who each have high standards of quality, privacy and security.
Clicking on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links may track your actions by using a cookie saved to your device. You can read more about cookies on this website above. Your actions are usually recorded as a referral from our website by this cookie. We may earn a small commission from the advertiser or advertising partner, at no cost to you, whether you make a purchase on their website or not.
We use advertising partners in these ways to help generate an income from the website, which allows us to continue our work and provide you with the best overall experience and valued information.
If you have any concerns about this we suggest you do not click on any adverts, sponsored or affiliate links found throughout the website.
EMAIL MARKETING MESSAGES & SUBSCRIPTION
Under the GDPR we use the consent lawful basis for anyone subscribing to our newsletter or marketing mailing list. We only collect certain data about you, as detailed in the "Processing of your personal date" above. Any email marketing messages we send are done so through an EMS, email marketing service provider. An EMS is a third party service provider of software / applications that allows marketers to send out email marketing campaigns to a list of users.
Email marketing messages that we send may contain tracking beacons / tracked clickable links or similar server technologies in order to track subscriber activity within email marketing messages. Where used, such marketing messages may record a range of data such as; times, dates, I.P addresses, opens, clicks, forwards, geographic and demographic data. Such data, within its limitations will show the activity each subscriber made for that email campaign.
Any email marketing messages we send are in accordance with the GDPR and the PECR. We provide you with an easy method to withdraw your consent (unsubscribe) or manage your preferences / the information we hold about you at any time. See any marketing messages for instructions on how to unsubscribe or manage your preferences.
Our EMS provider is Aweber.com. We hold the following information about you within our EMS system;
More information about Aweber can be found here: Aweber Permission Pledge.
